ALCHEMY OF SOULS PART 2
&lrm;還魂 &lrm;第二部
We have brought the liquor to be used for Jinyowon's ancestral rites.
&lrm;我們將辰曜院祭祀要用的酒送來了！
You have used different water to make it.
&lrm;釀酒的水不同了
You see, due to the drought for the past three years,
&lrm;因為連續三年乾旱
the well we always used had dried up.
&lrm;我們用來釀祭祀酒的井水已乾涸
So we had to use a different source.
&lrm;所以便換了水源
-Goodness!
&lrm;-天啊！ &lrm;-唉唷！
-No! -What--
&lrm;-這…
Make them again.
&lrm;重釀
Pardon?
&lrm;嗯？
But we have no water.
&lrm;可是我們沒水啊
How could we possibly make any liquor?
&lrm;沒有水我們如何釀酒？
Or could you let us use some of Jinyowon's water, my lady?
&lrm;若妳如此堅持 &lrm;不如讓我們借辰曜院的水一用
He can come inside and get it.
&lrm;讓他進來拿水就好
-Yes, my lady. -Me?
&lrm;-是 &lrm;-我？
Go.
&lrm;去吧
-Hurry. -Go.
&lrm;-快去 &lrm;-去吧
The young lady has disappeared from her room again.
&lrm;小姐又不在房裡了
Stay right here and wait for me.
&lrm;你在這裡等，不准亂跑
Yes, I will.
&lrm;好
How beautiful.
&lrm;好美喔
Is that liquor?
&lrm;那是酒嗎？
Here you go.
&lrm;來
This is of good quality.
&lrm;好酒
It is fragrant.
&lrm;香氣十足
Do you have more?
&lrm;你還有嗎？
I do have one more bottle.
&lrm;是還有一瓶
-Give it to me. -All right.
&lrm;-給我 &lrm;-好
My lady!
&lrm;小姐！
-Search over there. -Hurry.
&lrm;-去那邊找找！ &lrm;-快點…
Yes, here you go.
&lrm;喔，這裡
Wait.
&lrm;等…
How beautiful.
&lrm;好美
I have never seen such a beautiful woman before.
&lrm;我真是頭一次見到那麼美的女人
I think she is from the Jin family.
&lrm;她似乎是辰曜院的小姐
Young Lady Jin Cho-yeon is the only daughter they have.
&lrm;辰曜院的小姐只有一位 &lrm;就是剛才見到的陳超妍小姐
It is Jinyowon, after all.
&lrm;但那裡是辰曜院啊
He was likely possessed by a relic.
&lrm;他必定是被妖器迷惑了
They have forbidden outsiders from entering for three years.
&lrm;他們已經整整三年大門緊閉 &lrm;禁止外人進出
It must be teeming with ghosts.
&lrm;裡面肯定都是鬼啊
Whether she was a ghost or not, I hope I can see her again.
&lrm;就算是被鬼迷惑也好 &lrm;真想再見她一面
You little…
&lrm;你真的是…
Do not talk about ghosts when we are delivering funeral drinks.
&lrm;我們送酒來給喪家 &lrm;別把鬼掛在嘴邊觸霉頭
-Jeez. -My apologies.
&lrm;-真是的 &lrm;-對不起
Before we go inside…
&lrm;進喪家之前…
This charm will fend off ghosts. Take one.
&lrm;這是可以驅鬼的符咒，你們都帶著
What is this?
&lrm;這什麼啊？
This works on soul shifters too.
&lrm;聽說這個符咒還能驅逐還魂人呢
You remember Naksu, the soul shifter who devastated Songrim three years ago?
&lrm;還記得三年前把松林 &lrm;搞得一片狼藉的還魂人落壽嗎？
Her petrified body was ground to a powder
&lrm;這是用她石化的屍首磨成石粉
and used to make these charms.
&lrm;製成的符咒
-With her petrified body? -Yes.
&lrm;-落壽的石粉？ &lrm;-是啊
That is absurd.
&lrm;胡說
Her body is at the bottom of Lake Gyeongcheondaeho.
&lrm;落壽的屍首明明在敬天大湖裡
Jeez.
&lrm;受不了
I cannot believe you bought this. You wasted your money.
&lrm;真不知道你去哪道聽塗說 &lrm;你這錢白花了
Come on!
&lrm;真是的
Trust me on this.
&lrm;相信我啦
If you see a soul shifter,
&lrm;見到還魂人的時候
show it this charm that contains Naksu's energy and--
&lrm;只要拿出這個散發落壽氣息的符咒…
Did you do that?
&lrm;這是你弄的嗎？
No!
&lrm;不是！
Wait for me! Do not leave me!
&lrm;等等我！
-What is that? -Darn it!
&lrm;-那是什麼？ &lrm;-天啊！
Is this the deed of a soul shifter?
&lrm;這是被還魂人所殺的嗎？
-Who is that?
&lrm;-那是什麼？ &lrm;-什麼？
Is he a soul shifter?
&lrm;那是還魂人嗎？
Are we going to die?
&lrm;我們會不會死？
Stay away!
&lrm;速速退散！
-Go away. -Stay away!
&lrm;-走開 &lrm;-速速退散！
-Go away! -Leave!
&lrm;-走開！ &lrm;-快滾！
-Stay back! -We should go!
&lrm;-速速退散 &lrm;-我們快走
Wait.
&lrm;等等
He must not be a soul shifter.
&lrm;他好像不是還魂人
What is that?
&lrm;那是什麼？
A charm.
&lrm;原來是符咒
Does that fend off soul shifters?
&lrm;掌櫃說它能鎮住還魂人嗎？
Where did you get it? Gaema Village?
&lrm;你在哪買的？蓋馬谷？
Yes.
&lrm;嗯
-For how much? -One silver nyang.
&lrm;-你花了多少？ &lrm;-一兩銀
-For three? -No.
&lrm;-買三張嗎？ &lrm;-不是
For one. It was three nyang in total.
&lrm;一張一兩，共三兩
My lord.
&lrm;大人
That is expensive.
&lrm;你買貴了
That village lacks business ethics.
&lrm;蓋馬谷的人做生意真不厚道
You can get ten for one nyang elsewhere.
&lrm;有的地方十張才賣一兩
Really? Which village?
&lrm;真的嗎？哪裡？
That is not the point!
&lrm;現在那是重點嗎？
Darn it.
&lrm;可惡
You should get your money's worth.
&lrm;既然花了高價，自然要讓它物盡其用
If you want to live,
&lrm;如果還想活命
step aside and duck.
&lrm;就蹲下，別妨礙我
Despite having the ice stone,
&lrm;即便身懷冰石
can your Tansu skills only make one drop?
&lrm;你的彈水法也只能凝聚一滴水嗎？
Since your body has died already,
&lrm;你的肉身已死
you are a soul shifter just like me.
&lrm;你終究和我一樣是個還魂人
To others,
&lrm;對世人而言
we are both monsters.
&lrm;你我皆為怪物
Are you done?
&lrm;說完了嗎？
If not, hurry up because that one drop
&lrm;還沒就快點，否則那一滴水
is going to be quite painful.
&lrm;可是會非常痛
You do not deserve to say anything when you shifted into your son's body.
&lrm;為了續命而搶了兒子肉身的人 &lrm;居然還有臉教訓我？
So you are not a soul shifter
&lrm;所以你不是還魂人
but a mage who kills soul shifters.
&lrm;而是追殺還魂人的術士啊
Thank you for saving us, my lord.
&lrm;這位術士，謝謝你救了我們
-Is that a bottle of liquor? -Yes, my lord.
&lrm;-你腰上那是酒吧？ &lrm;-對
Goodness.
&lrm;天啊
His father shifted into his body?
&lrm;他的肉身竟被自己的爹給搶走
Poor boy.
&lrm;真是可憐
It is true that soul shifters petrify when they are dead.
&lrm;還魂人死後真的會石化耶
My lord.
&lrm;術士
Then Naksu died and was petrified, right?
&lrm;那落壽應該也這樣石化了吧？
I told you, I was right.
&lrm;我就說落壽石化了
These charms were indeed made with the remains of her petrified body.
&lrm;這符咒真的是用落壽的石粉做的啦
This charm will protect us from monsters like her.
&lrm;聽說這是連落壽那種怪物 &lrm;都能鎮住的符咒
My lord.
&lrm;這位術士
Would you like one?
&lrm;你要不要留一張？
This charm
&lrm;有這張符咒
will protect you from Naksu?
&lrm;連落壽都能鎮得住？
People must think
&lrm;看來世人
she is still alive.
&lrm;都相信落壽還活著
Goodness. Naksu is dead, of course.
&lrm;唉唷，落壽是死了
Despite her body lying in Lake Gyeongcheondaeho,
&lrm;即便她已石化，沉沒在敬天大湖裡
people are still terrified of her.
&lrm;但人們心中依然存有對她的恐懼
The men from Songrim will clean up here soon.
&lrm;稍後松林的人會來收拾這裡
My lord, what is your name?
&lrm;這位術士，敢問你的大名…
I think I know who he is.
&lrm;我好像知道他是誰了
He is the one who reached Hwansu
&lrm;他就是身懷冰石
with the ice stone.
&lrm;練就換水境界的
He is that mage.
&lrm;那位術士
The one whom Naksu almost killed?
&lrm;那位差點因落壽而送命的
Young Master Jang?
&lrm;張家少爺？
What kind of relationship did those two have?
&lrm;他跟落壽是什麼關係？
This charm will protect us from Naksu.
&lrm;這是能鎮住落壽的符咒
If I keep this with me,
&lrm;所以我要是帶著它
I will not be able to see you even if you come.
&lrm;妳就算來了，我也見不到妳
Naksu was a maid of his.
&lrm;落壽以前是服侍他的下人
She was also his betrothed.
&lrm;還是他即將娶進門的戀人
And in return for his unconditional love,
&lrm;可是他對落壽的疼惜和愛慕
she stabbed him
&lrm;最終
in the heart with a sword.
&lrm;卻換來落壽在他心頭刺下一劍
ALCHEMY OF SOULS PART 2
&lrm;還魂 &lrm;第二部
The energy of the sky rules the wind, clouds, and rain.
&lrm;掌管了風、雲、雨的天氣
This energy reached the ground and created a huge form of energy.
&lrm;這股氣息觸及大地，形成巨大的水氣
A country was built around Lake Gyeongcheondaeho,
&lrm;以蘊含其氣息的敬天大湖為中心
a lake that embodied that energy.
&lrm;建立了國家
The name of the country was Daeho
&lrm;因為國家坐擁一座大湖
due to the enormous lake it had.
&lrm;故得名大湖國
This story is about the mages of Daeho, a place that does not exist
&lrm;這個故事不存在於歷史和地圖上
in both history books or maps.
&lrm;是屬於大湖國術士的故事
That looks delicious.
&lrm;看起來好好吃
-Thank you. -Enjoy.
&lrm;-走吧 &lrm;-請慢用
It must be a soul shifter.
&lrm;看來又出現還魂人了
I am terrified.
&lrm;好可怕
Did you lose her?
&lrm;追丟了嗎？
She fled into Jinyowon, of all places.
&lrm;她偏偏躲進了辰曜院
Jinyowon?
&lrm;辰曜院？
JINYOWON
&lrm;（辰曜院）
Outsiders are not allowed to enter Jinyowon.
&lrm;外人不得進入辰曜院
I am aware that for the past three years,
&lrm;我知道這三年來
Jinyowon has forbidden outsiders from entering.
&lrm;辰曜院大門緊閉，一律不許外人進出
But this is an urgent situation. A soul shifter has hidden inside.
&lrm;但事出緊急，有還魂人躲進了辰曜院
Ask Lady Jin to come and see me.
&lrm;去通報院長說我想親自見她一面
She will still say no.
&lrm;院長是不會見你的
He is the leader of Songrim.
&lrm;這位可是松林的首領
How dare a low-ranking priestess refuse to relay his message?
&lrm;妳區區一名低階神女
-My apologies. -Open the gate this instant!
&lrm;-請見諒 &lrm;-立刻將門打開！
Young Lady Jin.
&lrm;超妍小姐
I have not seen you for three years.
&lrm;三年沒見了
Have you been well?
&lrm;這段日子妳過得好嗎？
I did not come out here to send my regards.
&lrm;我出來並非為了寒暄
My mother refuses to allow outsiders to enter Jinyowon.
&lrm;家母不允許外人進出辰曜院
So you should go.
&lrm;諸位還是請回吧
It is a dangerous situation.
&lrm;情況危急
A soul shifter has harmed dozens of lives at Yeongpo Dock.
&lrm;那個還魂人在榮浦渡口傷了數十人
The people of Jinyowon could get hurt too.
&lrm;辰曜院的人很可能也會受害
Just like my father did?
&lrm;就像我爹那樣嗎？
How could you possibly save anyone when you failed to save
&lrm;你都沒能從還魂人手中救下準岳丈了
the father of your betrothed?
&lrm;如今你還想救誰？
After what happened,
&lrm;當年的事…
you never gave me the chance to apologize.
&lrm;妳從未給我道歉的機會
So it laid heavy on my heart.
&lrm;所以我一直愧疚至今
Then keep feeling guilty.
&lrm;那就繼續愧疚吧
I hope you never forget it.
&lrm;千萬別因淡忘而放下
Young Lady Jin.
&lrm;超妍小姐
You should go.
&lrm;請回吧
Did someone
&lrm;方才
just enter Jinyowon?
&lrm;有人闖進來嗎？
Yes.
&lrm;是
I believe it was Jang Uk.
&lrm;我想應該是張煜
He has been chasing the soul shifter with us.
&lrm;他正和我們一起追捕還魂人
Jang Uk?
&lrm;張煜？
Are you saying he just stepped inside?
&lrm;你是說他闖進這裡面了？
He is only obeying
&lrm;阿煜
the order of the royal family and the Unanimous Assembly.
&lrm;正奉王室和萬長會之命在追捕還魂人
I shall close the gate.
&lrm;我要關門了
You should go.
&lrm;你們請回吧
There is no doubt that Uk will catch the soul shifter.
&lrm;張煜已經進去了 &lrm;他一定會抓到還魂人
We can just wait here.
&lrm;我們在這裡等就行了
Sure.
&lrm;好
Jang Uk
&lrm;張煜
is in Jinyowon?
&lrm;進了我們家門嗎？
Yes.
&lrm;對
He is here to catch the soul shifter in hiding.
&lrm;他進來追捕躲在這裡的還魂人
Is Bu-yeon still in the annex as she was told?
&lrm;復妍呢？她有乖乖待在別院吧？
There is a barrier around her room,
&lrm;關著復妍姐姐的別院廂房
so it will be near invisible to the naked eye.
&lrm;有結界掩蔽，肉眼不易發現
Jang Uk will never find her.
&lrm;她不會碰到張煜的
You must have shifted a long time ago.
&lrm;看來妳還魂很久了
What is this?
&lrm;這是什麼？
What is this place?
&lrm;這是什麼地方？
A prison?
&lrm;牢房嗎？
Do not touch that.
&lrm;別碰
Who are you? How did you get in here?
&lrm;你是誰？怎麼進來的？
You must be insane.
&lrm;妳瘋了吧
You seem to be a lousy Jinyowon priestess.
&lrm;妳看起來只是辰曜院的一介小神女
How dare you aim that fire poker at me?
&lrm;竟敢拿撥火棍對著我？
Incredible.
&lrm;好厲害
Did you enter this room after breaking the surrounding barrier?
&lrm;你是直接打破 &lrm;這房間的結界進來的嗎？
As a priestess, you must know who I am.
&lrm;妳若是辰曜院的神女 &lrm;那應該知道我的身分
Who are you?
&lrm;妳是誰？
And what is this place?
&lrm;這又是什麼地方？
Is this a prison?
&lrm;這是牢房嗎？
Are you locked in here?
&lrm;而妳被關在這裡？
It is not a prison.
&lrm;這不是牢房
I could use this as a step.
&lrm;這樣我爬上去就輕鬆多了
Throw this onto the wall too.
&lrm;你也把這個插進牆壁吧
What?
&lrm;什麼？
Is it too flat?
&lrm;還是太寬插不進去？
Then…
&lrm;那…
Is this better? Or this?
&lrm;這個會比較好嗎？還是這個？
Which one would be better?
&lrm;哪一個比較好？
You must be locked up here.
&lrm;看來妳確實是被關在這裡
Are they no good?
&lrm;這個不好用嗎？
You must be ill.
&lrm;好像還有點病
Would this be better?
&lrm;這個會比較好嗎？
Are you leaving?
&lrm;你要走了嗎？
All right, then take me with you.
&lrm;那你帶我一起出去吧
You want
&lrm;妳說
to leave with me?
&lrm;妳要跟我走？
I have not gone out in ages.
&lrm;我已經很久沒呼吸到外面的空氣了
I smell the flowers on your clothing.
&lrm;你的衣服上染了花香
The roses must have bloomed already.
&lrm;看來外頭的薔薇都開了
Look.
&lrm;姑娘
I understand that you are crazy about going outside.
&lrm;我明白妳很想出去摘花別在頭上
But I cannot help you.
&lrm;但妳抓錯地方了
You can use that instead to go outside.
&lrm;應該抓那裡才對，抓著繩子爬出去吧
But that will be exhausting.
&lrm;抓著繩子爬太累了
-I want to go with you. -Hey, Lousy Priestess.
&lrm;-我要跟你一起走 &lrm;-喂，小神女
Step back unless you want to end up like that fire poker.
&lrm;妳要是不想像那支撥火棍一樣 &lrm;被插在牆上，就乖乖放手
I am not used
&lrm;我不習慣
to having people stand so close.
&lrm;有人距離我這麼近
That is a pretty stone.
&lrm;你有一顆漂亮的石頭耶
You must have
&lrm;你身上
the energy of the sky.
&lrm;竟然懷有蒼天之力
I guess you are not all that lousy.
&lrm;看來妳不是什麼小神女
You.
&lrm;妳
Can you see what is inside me?
&lrm;看得見我體內的東西？
Yes.
&lrm;嗯
I can see the energy of the world.
&lrm;我看得見這世間所有的力量
I have heard of a priestess who could do that.
&lrm;我是聽說過有神女 &lrm;可以用肉眼看見力量
So it was you?
&lrm;妳就是那種人嗎？
Tell me. Who are you?
&lrm;妳究竟是誰？
I cannot reveal who I am due to a certain reason.
&lrm;礙於某些原因 &lrm;我沒辦法向你表明身分
But once you find out who I am,
&lrm;不過你一旦知道我是誰
you will definitely want to take me out of here.
&lrm;必定會想將我從這裡帶走
Where is Jang Uk?
&lrm;張煜呢？
I found traces of his fight with the soul shifter.
&lrm;到處都有他與還魂人打鬥的痕跡
Even near Bu-yeon's annex?
&lrm;姐姐的別院也有嗎？
I did not look there due to the barrier.
&lrm;那裡有結界，屬下沒去看
No. That is the most vulnerable place.
&lrm;不行，那裡最危險
It would be terrible if he ever were to run into her.
&lrm;萬一讓張煜見到姐姐就不好了
Seeing how they even imprisoned you with a barrier,
&lrm;看她們還費心布下結界將妳關在這
I guess you are not simply crazy.
&lrm;確實不像只為了關一個瘋子
If you get me out of here, I will tell you who I am.
&lrm;你要是帶我出去，我就告訴你我是誰
You will be utterly shocked.
&lrm;你絕對會大吃一驚
-Forget it. -Are you not curious about me?
&lrm;-算了吧 &lrm;-你不想知道我是誰嗎？
Jinyowon and I have bad blood.
&lrm;我跟辰曜院已經有深仇大恨
I do not want to let you out and worsen our relationship even more.
&lrm;我不想再因為放妳出去 &lrm;跟辰曜院結下更大的梁子
You have bad blood with Jinyowon?
&lrm;你跟辰曜院有過節？
You.
&lrm;喂
Was this to help you escape?
&lrm;妳說這是用來逃跑的吧？
Well, it is pretty lousy.
&lrm;還真簡陋
It took me three whole days to make that.
&lrm;我可是花了三天才掛上去的
Three days?
&lrm;三天？
Hey!
&lrm;喂！
If you do not want to take me, fine.
&lrm;你不帶我走就算了
But did you have to do that?
&lrm;幹嘛把我的繩子扯下來？
They will suspect me if you escape soon after I leave.
&lrm;妳要是在我離開後馬上逃走 &lrm;她們必然會誤會我
I want to avoid unnecessary trouble.
&lrm;我得避免不必要的紛爭
It took you three days, right?
&lrm;妳不是只要花三天嗎？
So postpone your escape by three days so it will not affect me.
&lrm;妳就晚個三天再逃吧 &lrm;這樣就跟我無關了
It will just be an outing, not an escape.
&lrm;我不是要逃，只是想出門走走
Even if I get out of here,
&lrm;反正我就算離開這裡
I have no choice but to return.
&lrm;終究也只能回來
Why did they lock up such an incredible priestess?
&lrm;妳這麼厲害的神女 &lrm;為何會被關在這裡？
What crime are you guilty of?
&lrm;妳犯了什麼罪？
Being alive.
&lrm;活下來
Existing in this world.
&lrm;存在於這個世間
I am guilty
&lrm;本不該存活
of existing in this world when I should not.
&lrm;卻還留在這世間，這就是我的罪名
I am someone who died a long time ago.
&lrm;我從很久以前就已經是個死人了
It must have been Jang Uk's doing.
&lrm;這應該是張煜所為
He must have come very close to the annex.
&lrm;他可能來過別院門口了
Bu-yeon.
&lrm;姐姐
Did anyone come in here?
&lrm;這裡有沒有人進來過？
No.
&lrm;沒有啊
Who else could come in here except for you and Mother?
&lrm;這裡除了妳跟娘，還有誰會進來？
What is the matter?
&lrm;怎麼了？
Did something happen?
&lrm;出什麼事了嗎？
A soul shifter entered and hid in Jinyowon.
&lrm;有還魂人躲進辰曜院
A mage also entered to catch her
&lrm;因此有一名術士闖進來抓人
and caused havoc.
&lrm;鬧出了不小的動靜
A soul shifter?
&lrm;還魂人？
A monster whose soul is different from its body?
&lrm;肉身與靈魂不同的怪物？
Yes.
&lrm;嗯
But we killed the soul shifter, so do not worry.
&lrm;不過還魂人已經抓到了，妳不必擔心
So he was a mage who came here to kill the soul shifter.
&lrm;原來他是來抓還魂人的術士
This will be enough to help you escape.
&lrm;這樣妳應該就能爬出去了
Remember what I said.
&lrm;我再說一次
Do not tell them about me and wait before you get out.
&lrm;不准跟她們提起我 &lrm;而且要過段時間再出去
I will.
&lrm;好
Can you do two more?
&lrm;再幫我插兩個吧
I am not as tall as you.
&lrm;我不像你手長腳長的
Will two suffice?
&lrm;多兩個夠嗎？
-You are pretty short. -Then you will do three?
&lrm;-妳手腳那麼短 &lrm;-那你要幫我插三個嗎？
Thanks.
&lrm;謝謝
Jeez.
&lrm;真是的
By the way, why are you helping me?
&lrm;不過你為什麼要幫我啊？
Why the change of heart?
&lrm;你怎麼會突然改變心意？
Because we are guilty of the same crime.
&lrm;因為妳的罪名跟我差不多
I am also guilty of existing
&lrm;不該存在
when I should not.
&lrm;卻存活下來了
Someone guilty of the same crime…
&lrm;跟我背負同樣罪名的人…
The roses must have really bloomed.
&lrm;看來外頭的薔薇真的開了
SONGRIM
&lrm;（松林）
This soul shifter entered a cargo boat at Yeongpo Dock
&lrm;這個還魂人闖進榮浦渡口的貨船
and slaughtered everyone inside.
&lrm;屠殺了船上的所有人
We are constantly finding soul shifters running rampant.
&lrm;失控的還魂人接二連三地出現
And Uk killed them all.
&lrm;還都是被阿煜抓到的
That is because everyone agreed that would be how to make use of Jang Uk,
&lrm;畢竟讓身懷冰石存活的張煜 &lrm;發揮此等用處
who was reborn with the power of the ice stone.
&lrm;就是所有人的決議啊
That is not true.
&lrm;說什麼決議？
He just complied with that decision.
&lrm;阿煜只是順你們的意罷了
Are you still
&lrm;你現在
awkward around him?
&lrm;見到阿煜還有疙瘩嗎？
Yul has returned to Seoho Fortress.
&lrm;阿律已經回西湖城了
You are the only friend he has.
&lrm;你現在是他唯一的朋友
You should not distance yourself from him.
&lrm;要是連你都疏遠他，他該如何是好？
That is not my intention.
&lrm;我沒有疏遠他
I just
&lrm;我只是
do not know how to act around him.
&lrm;不知道該怎麼對待他
I cannot laud him by claiming to envy the great power he holds.
&lrm;他擁有如此強大的力量 &lrm;我又不能恭喜他或隨之起舞
But I cannot empathize with him
&lrm;也不能慰問他的辛勞
and tell him to give up either.
&lrm;要他放棄
Things are not how they used to be.
&lrm;我們無法像以前那樣自在相處
Since he used the ice stone's power
&lrm;他今天追捕還魂人
to kill this soul shifter,
&lrm;運用了體內的冰石之力
he will have trouble sleeping tonight as well.
&lrm;今夜想必又徹夜難眠了
Oh, dear.
&lrm;唉唷
Songrim told me.
&lrm;我接到松林的消息了
Young Master, are you all right?
&lrm;少爺，你還好嗎？
I am always fine.
&lrm;我一直都很好
Worrying about me will be the death of you.
&lrm;金道主，妳再這麼操心，小心折壽
I told you not to worry.
&lrm;都說了不用這麼擔心我
Since you used that sword,
&lrm;你用了那把劍
you will struggle tonight as well.
&lrm;想必今夜肯定又會很難熬
I am used to it now.
&lrm;又不是第一次了
It is bearable.
&lrm;我已經習以為常，還撐得住
Did you heat up his room?
&lrm;少爺房裡暖了吧？
Prepare some strong liquor and place a brazier inside.
&lrm;幫他準備烈酒，再送盆火爐進去
I am too scared to enter his room.
&lrm;我實在不太敢進少爺房裡
I get goosebumps, and chills run down my spine
&lrm;我只要靠近就會全身起雞皮疙瘩
-if I am nearby. -Goodness.
&lrm;-不停打冷顫 &lrm;-真是的
Light the brazier, and I will carry it inside.
&lrm;那你準備火爐就好，我送進去
Yes, ma'am.
&lrm;好的
-Save me. -Please help me.
&lrm;-救我 &lrm;-幫幫我
I do not want to die.
&lrm;我不想死
Give me the ice stone!
&lrm;把冰石交出來！
Since he used the energy of the sky,
&lrm;身為人類，運用了蒼天之力
the wraiths swarm toward him to feed on that power.
&lrm;便會有許多鬼魂 &lrm;為了借用那股力量蜂擁而至
They are noisy, cold, unsightly, and pitiful.
&lrm;他們喧囂、陰涼、醜陋、可悲
That is the price one must pay for taking the ice stone
&lrm;那可謂身懷冰石，取得蒼天之力
and using the energy of the sky.
&lrm;所伴隨的痛苦
Yeongpo Dock will be closed for now
&lrm;榮浦渡口有太多人手遭還魂人殺害
You must deliver the goods to Wol Fortress by land.
&lrm;要送到月城的東西可能得走陸路了
Daegangtongun will be the quickest.
&lrm;大江通運速度最快
Yes, my lord.
&lrm;好的
Young Master Park finally looks like the leader of Songrim.
&lrm;當具少爺現在已經很有 &lrm;商會首領架勢了
He may not have been the best at casting spells,
&lrm;當具首領雖然在法術方面 &lrm;並非天賦異稟
but he is an excellent businessman.
&lrm;但卻是很出色的生意人
-Young Lady Heo. -Yes?
&lrm;-小姐 &lrm;-嗯？
Has Young Lady Heo decided not to return to Wol Fortress?
&lrm;贇鈺小姐這是不打算再回月城了嗎？
She is tending to the body that the Queen's soul resides in.
&lrm;王妃還魂的身子是贇鈺在照料
So she cannot leave.
&lrm;她走不了
Did you say she visited your place again?
&lrm;聽說她前兩天又往你們家跑啦？
Yes, my lord.
&lrm;是啊
She is worried about how our young master cannot sleep well,
&lrm;她因為擔心我家少爺睡不好
so she always brings him medicine that she concocts.
&lrm;每回都堅持親自幫他煎藥送過來
And has Uk ever thanked her by offering her some tea?
&lrm;那阿煜會感謝她 &lrm;請她一起喝杯茶嗎？
I understand how she feels, so I try my best to help out.
&lrm;我明白贇鈺小姐的心情 &lrm;也試過幫她一把
But it is difficult.
&lrm;但就是無法如我所願
Goodness.
&lrm;唉唷
I keep telling her to give up on him,
&lrm;我也告訴過她該放下了
but it is not working.
&lrm;但一樣無法如我所願
I will keep trying.
&lrm;我會繼續想辦法的
Goodness. By the way, will you be visiting Park Jin?
&lrm;唉唷，妳要去找朴進吧？
-Yes, my lord. -If you do,
&lrm;-對 &lrm;-妳去的時候
can you please dissuade him
&lrm;想辦法勸勸他
from continuing his new hobby?
&lrm;叫他克制一下新的興趣
All the people of Songrim have pickled tongues thanks to him.
&lrm;拜他所賜，松林人的舌頭 &lrm;都要變醃舌頭了
Pickled tongues?
&lrm;醃舌頭？
Our tongues are a mess.
&lrm;舌頭都快爛了
What could he possibly be doing?
&lrm;他為何會把你們舌頭搞爛？
Goodness.
&lrm;唉唷
My lord.
&lrm;首領
What are you up to?
&lrm;你在做什麼？
Hello, Maidservant Kim.
&lrm;金道主，妳來啦
I am making cubed radish kimchi today.
&lrm;我今天在醃辣蘿蔔塊
You are making all of this?
&lrm;這些都要醃啊？
You have no idea how delighted those in the kitchen are
&lrm;妳都不知道我醃好辣白菜拿去廚房
whenever I give them new batches of kimchi.
&lrm;他們有多開心
Right.
&lrm;是喔
I did hear that you gave them five crocks
&lrm;聽聞先前你也醃了
of mustard leaf kimchi and green onion kimchi last time.
&lrm;五缸辣芥菜和辣拌蔥送過去
It was not that tiring to make,
&lrm;那一點也不費力
and I only did it to kill time.
&lrm;我本是當作消遣醃醃看
But they seem to be waiting for my kimchi now.
&lrm;沒想到大家現在似乎都等不及了
I do not think they are that desperate for the kimchi.
&lrm;我倒是不覺得他們有這麼期待
There is no need for all this.
&lrm;你何必自己找事做呢？
They cannot openly ask for more since they are intimidated by me.
&lrm;他們覺得我不好親近 &lrm;想請我多醃一些又羞於啟齒
But I am not that dense.
&lrm;但我都看出來了
I ought to give them more.
&lrm;自然應該幫他們醃
I need more garlic.
&lrm;大蒜不太夠
I will be back.
&lrm;妳稍等一會
Gosh, everyone told me to stop him.
&lrm;大家都拜託我阻止他耶
I get why Maidservant Park said this was driving her crazy.
&lrm;我總算明白朴道主為何說她快瘋了
This is too much to throw away.
&lrm;這些要是都醃下去，丟也丟不得
It will only torment the eater.
&lrm;只是苦了吃的人
I see.
&lrm;嗯
My lord, I need some radish.
&lrm;首領，我需要一些蘿蔔
Can I use those?
&lrm;我能不能帶一點走？
Sure.
&lrm;可以啊
But then I will not have enough to make cubed radish kimchi with.
&lrm;不過這樣我似乎會不夠醃
Come on. This is already enough.
&lrm;唉唷，這樣已經夠多了
They will appreciate it more if it is not abundant.
&lrm;不夠吃才會意猶未盡啊
That is true.
&lrm;-這麼說也是 &lrm;-對啊
-Have a seat. -Yes, my lord.
&lrm;-坐吧 &lrm;-好
Do you feel empty inside after stepping down from being a leader?
&lrm;你卸下首領的職務後 &lrm;覺得百無聊賴嗎？
I tend to the field and the flowers.
&lrm;我現在能種田、種花
I also do housework. It is all quite fun.
&lrm;還能打理家務，別有一番趣味
You have planted many balsam seeds.
&lrm;你種了好多鳳仙花
Young Master Jang
&lrm;我家少爺
is still very ill.
&lrm;至今還是備受煎熬
I am afraid
&lrm;今年
I will have to be by his side this year as well.
&lrm;我恐怕還是得陪在他身邊
I understand.
&lrm;我都明白
Three years ago,
&lrm;三年前發生那些事
you took responsibility for everything and stepped down.
&lrm;你一肩扛起所有責任，退下首領之位
I did not once dissuade you.
&lrm;我不僅沒有阻攔你
Rather, I brazenly thanked you.
&lrm;還厚顏無恥地向你道謝
I was only relieved that my young master
&lrm;我以為你這麼做就能讓我家少爺
was spared.
&lrm;平安無事了
We have not peeled the garlic yet, but you are already crying.
&lrm;都還沒開始剝大蒜 &lrm;妳可不能這麼早就流淚
We need to peel all of these.
&lrm;我們得把這些都剝完
Yes, my lord.
&lrm;好
I will peel them all for you.
&lrm;我來幫你把它們通通剝完
But the kimchi will be too bitter if you put them all in.
&lrm;不過這些大蒜若都加進去恐怕會很苦
The bigger the amount, the tastier it will be.
&lrm;任何東西都要夠多才有味道
I need some garlic too, so let me take half.
&lrm;我也需要大蒜，一半讓我帶走吧
Will the kimchi still be tasty?
&lrm;這樣還會好吃嗎？
Half is more than enough.
&lrm;這些就夠了
I see.
&lrm;喔
Jinyowon is preparing for a wedding?
&lrm;辰曜院似乎在籌措婚事？
Do you remember how we placed
&lrm;你還記得以前超妍小姐籌措婚事時
Young Lady Jin's wedding supplies in the storage?
&lrm;準備的東西都存放在商會庫房吧？
Jinyowon asked for them back today.
&lrm;今天辰曜院要我們將東西送過去
Someone must be getting married.
&lrm;可能有人要成親了
But if someone from the Jin family is getting married,
&lrm;若是陳家有人要成親
it can only mean Young Lady Jin.
&lrm;那不就只有陳超妍小姐一人嗎？
The wedding date has been set already?
&lrm;怎麼連婚期都定了？
This is too sudden, Mother.
&lrm;娘，這太突然了
It was not easy to find a suitor.
&lrm;那是好不容易找到的女婿人選
She must obey my words.
&lrm;她必須遵從我的意思
Mother.
&lrm;娘
Why are you so cruel?
&lrm;妳為何要如此殘忍？
As I expected,
&lrm;果然還是因為
is she not Bu-yeon,
&lrm;她不是復妍姐姐
but that other woman?
&lrm;而是那個女人吧？
Jin Cho-yeon.
&lrm;陳超妍
She is Bu-yeon.
&lrm;她是復妍
The original soul was already dead
&lrm;那個女人的靈魂
when we retrieved the body from the lake three years ago.
&lrm;早在三年前我們將她 &lrm;撈出敬天大湖時就已消亡
That body belongs to my daughter, Jin Bu-yeon.
&lrm;那身子是我女兒陳復妍的
Bu-yeon.
&lrm;復妍
Yes, Mother.
&lrm;是，娘
I am getting married?
&lrm;我要成親？
Does that mean I will leave this room?
&lrm;成親後我會離開這間房嗎？
He will be married into the family.
&lrm;對方會入贅進陳家
Once your husband arrives for the wedding,
&lrm;等到大婚之日，新郎進門
you will continue living in this room.
&lrm;妳也只要像現在一樣 &lrm;繼續住在這裡就好
If I cannot get out of here, why must I get married?
&lrm;如果我還得繼續被關在這裡 &lrm;那為何還要成親？
Because we need a girl who will lead Jinyowon in the future.
&lrm;我們必須有子嗣來繼承辰曜院啊
Children with the greatest divine powers
&lrm;擁有最強神力的孩子
always come from the eldest daughters.
&lrm;皆是由長女所生
Give birth to a beautiful daughter with great divine powers.
&lrm;生個擁有強大神力的漂亮女兒吧
So you expect me to stay locked up here and just give birth?
&lrm;言下之意是要我 &lrm;繼續被關在這裡生孩子嗎？
No.
&lrm;我不要
I do not want that kind of marriage.
&lrm;我不想要那樣的婚姻
It has already been decided.
&lrm;事情已成定局
You just need to follow my orders.
&lrm;妳只需要聽從我的指示
If I get married like you want me to,
&lrm;若遵從妳的意思成親
I will forever be stuck here.
&lrm;就表示我將永遠被困在這個房間
Bu-yeon.
&lrm;復妍
It took me many years to find you again.
&lrm;妳是我好不容易失而復得的女兒
Marry the man I have chosen for you
&lrm;妳就和為娘選定的男人成親
and stay by my side forever.
&lrm;一輩子陪在我身邊吧
Mother.
&lrm;娘
Who will Bu-yeon
&lrm;要和姐姐成親的人
get married to?
&lrm;是誰？
He is from the Seo family at Seoho Fortress.
&lrm;他是來自西湖城的徐家人
He will temporarily stay at Chwiseonru upon arrival.
&lrm;他抵達後會暫住取仙樓
The wedding will take place at his uncle's house.
&lrm;而後將借他舅父的房子舉行婚禮
He is excellent husband material.
&lrm;他可是和任何人相比 &lrm;都毫不遜色的夫婿人選
We will arrive at Daeho Fortress soon.
&lrm;我們即將抵達大湖城
Has it been three years for you?
&lrm;阿律，你三年沒回來了吧？
Yes.
&lrm;是啊
I did not know it would take me this long to return.
&lrm;時隔三年，我總算能回來了
But Yul,
&lrm;不過阿律
why did Master Heo forbid you from returning to Daeho Fortress?
&lrm;許琰大夫為何交代 &lrm;千萬別讓你回到大湖城？
I doubt you caused any kind of trouble.
&lrm;你不可能闖禍
Did you have bad blood with someone at Songrim?
&lrm;難道你和松林的人有嫌隙嗎？
He was protecting me.
&lrm;他是在保護我
And I was cowardly enough to listen.
&lrm;而我也卑怯地遵從了他的意思
Due to the ongoing drought, the water level has dropped.
&lrm;也許是旱災持續三年的緣故 &lrm;湖水減少了許多
Its energy is weak now.
&lrm;水氣也變弱了
I heard they are planning to perform a rite for the lake again.
&lrm;所以我聽聞他們想再次舉行敬天大祭
The Unanimous Assembly will be discussing it.
&lrm;萬長會上將討論那件事
But to do that,
&lrm;若要舉行大祭
they will need the help of Jinyowon's priestesses.
&lrm;辰曜院神女的力量將迫切為人所需 &lrm;也會變得更重要
Jang Uk of Songrim
&lrm;松林的張煜
caught and retrieved the soul of the 29th soul shifter.
&lrm;抓到了第29個還魂人，並收復其靈魂
Then as usual,
&lrm;那就一如往常
the Crown Prince shall visit him and reward him with 1,000 gold nyang.
&lrm;由世子登門拜訪張煜 &lrm;賜他一千兩黃金
Please allow Cheonbugwan
&lrm;往後就讓天府館的人
to deliver them instead of His Royal Highness from now on.
&lrm;代替世子邸下前去轉交吧
I decline.
&lrm;不
I ask that the Crown Prince reward Uk himself as always.
&lrm;請像往常一樣 &lrm;讓世子邸下親自賜予張煜
Jang Uk has been earning 1,000 gold nyang every time.
&lrm;張煜每次皆收取一千兩黃金
At this rate, he will be the richest man in Daeho.
&lrm;我看照這麼下去 &lrm;他要成為大湖國首富了
If that is the price for taking all the credit,
&lrm;倘若一千兩黃金能換取所有功勞
then you should do it happily.
&lrm;那您應該樂意之至
The people of Daeho believe you have ordered Jang Uk
&lrm;大湖國的人都以為是您派張煜
to kill all the monsters.
&lrm;去追捕怪物
They praise you for being born under the King's Star.
&lrm;因此讚頌您不愧貴為帝王星
On the other hand,
&lrm;然而
they call Uk a monster who catches other monsters.
&lrm;張煜卻被認為是追捕怪物的怪物
They are terrified and avoid him.
&lrm;人人害怕得避之唯恐不及
He brought that upon himself.
&lrm;那是他自找的
Why is he carrying Naksu's sword that once killed him?
&lrm;他為何非得將落壽刺穿他的劍 &lrm;帶在身邊呢？
Some say he is bearing a bitter grudge,
&lrm;有些人說他心懷深仇大恨
while others say he is just painfully in love with her.
&lrm;有些人則說那是他刻骨銘心的愛戀
What do you think, Your Royal Highness?
&lrm;在您看來呢？
He is nothing but a lunatic.
&lrm;他就是個瘋子
He chose to carry her sword
&lrm;非得拿著那女人的劍
and kill soul shifters who are just like her.
&lrm;收復和她一樣的還魂人靈魂
He feels dark and ominous.
&lrm;是個陰沉晦氣之人
That is how people perceive him as of now.
&lrm;那便是現在人們眼中的張煜
Is that not what you wanted in the first place?
&lrm;那不正是您所期待的結果嗎？
He is living the life you wanted for him.
&lrm;既然他已如您所願過著那種生活
So please visit him,
&lrm;就請您親自走一趟
and praise and congratulate that ominous lunatic yourself.
&lrm;鼓勵與表揚那個晦氣的瘋子
Visiting the now-empty Jeongjingak always makes me forlorn.
&lrm;這空無一人的精進閣 &lrm;每每都令我心情備感沉重
Since every mage except Jang Uk has left,
&lrm;所有術士皆離去，僅剩張煜一人
the energy that fills this place must be his own.
&lrm;充斥此處的氣息肯定來自張煜
I heard it is always dark and cold where he is.
&lrm;據說他所在之處總是陰暗又寒冷
I am here to reward you for killing the soul shifter.
&lrm;我來賜予你本次抓到還魂人的獎賞
Thank you, Your Royal Highness.
&lrm;每次都很感謝您
You can leave it and go.
&lrm;您放著就請回吧
How dare he not accept it in person?
&lrm;你竟敢不下來親自接受賞賜？
Shall I call him back?
&lrm;需要小的去叫他下來嗎？
That is fine.
&lrm;罷了
I heard you followed the soul shifter into Jinyowon.
&lrm;聽說你這次追還魂人追進了辰曜院
How did you get in when they forbade outsiders from entering?
&lrm;我聽聞那裡禁止外人進出 &lrm;你是如何潛入的？
No one can stop me from going anywhere.
&lrm;沒人能阻止我去任何地方
And I am used to feeling unwelcome.
&lrm;而且我早已習慣不受歡迎的感覺了
Is that why you drink alone in this dark and gloomy place?
&lrm;所以你才在這陰森的地方 &lrm;獨自喝著酒嗎？
Park Dang-gu used to be so affectionate toward you.
&lrm;朴當具當初還表現得和你那麼要好
Then again,
&lrm;也是
I do not blame him. His wedding fell through because of you.
&lrm;你害他辦不成婚禮 &lrm;一同飲酒作樂應該很彆扭
And Seo Yul is at Seoho Fortress.
&lrm;徐律也回西湖城了
I heard all the Jeongjingak mages left because of you.
&lrm;聽說精進閣的術士也因你全數離去
You are truly all alone.
&lrm;你徹底孑然一身了
I would rather be blunt than sugarcoat things.
&lrm;我可不會怕傷到你的心就拐彎抹角
Hey, why do you drink such strong liquor?
&lrm;喂，你喝這麼烈的酒做什麼？
My insides are melting.
&lrm;我的五臟六腑都要燒起來了
You should force yourself to have it.
&lrm;即使酒很烈，您最好還是喝下去
The liquor will protect you from the chill emitted by wraiths.
&lrm;烈酒有助於抵擋鬼魂散發的寒氣
Wraiths?
&lrm;鬼魂？
But this is Jeongjingak.
&lrm;這裡可是精進閣
Did you not hear?
&lrm;您沒聽說嗎？
Wraiths follow me everywhere.
&lrm;那些東西一直跟在我身邊
What?
&lrm;不是啊
But it is broad daylight.
&lrm;你大白天的胡謅什麼？
That is absurd.
&lrm;太荒謬了
Feel free to leave if you feel uncomfortable.
&lrm;您若感到不適，大可起身離開
You must not have come here because you missed me.
&lrm;您應該也不是想我才來的
Why do you ask me to reward you every time if you know how uncomfortable I am?
&lrm;你明知如此 &lrm;為何每次都要我賜你賞金？
You do not lack money.
&lrm;你又不缺錢
It makes me feel at ease to use this power
&lrm;那樣我心裡比較好過 &lrm;將我擁有的力量
only to atone for my sins and be rewarded.
&lrm;用於贖罪並獲取報酬 &lrm;能讓我心安理得
I take credit for punishing and rewarding you.
&lrm;那麼我向你問罪並給你賞金 &lrm;所獲得的讚頌
I must look like a joke to you.
&lrm;對你而言肯定不足掛齒吧
This is what I dislike about you.
&lrm;我就是討厭你這一點
You look down on me and mock me for the things I desire and obsess over.
&lrm;你彷彿瞧不起並嘲弄 &lrm;我渴望與執迷的一切
That is what offends me.
&lrm;這令我相當不悅
And you should be.
&lrm;您理當要感到不悅
That is exactly why I am doing this.
&lrm;這正是我乖乖做這份差事的目的
I am too intimidating to be considered acting out of stupidity.
&lrm;您不敢將我的行為視為虛張聲勢
Yet your ego does not let you accept that I am acting out of vigor.
&lrm;然而要您承認這是氣勢使然 &lrm;又會傷自尊
I am sure it bothers you.
&lrm;想必您十分困擾
You are right.
&lrm;沒錯
You are always as annoying as a splinter in my finger.
&lrm;你就像扎在指甲裡的尖刺 &lrm;總令人看不順眼
A splinter in your finger?
&lrm;扎在指甲裡的尖刺？
What a joke.
&lrm;真是微不足道
Did Jin Mu tell you
&lrm;是陳武要您
to think that of me to make you feel better?
&lrm;把我當成微不足道的存在嗎？
Am I not too strong
&lrm;您不覺得我這根刺
and too significant to be a mere splinter?
&lrm;太過強大了嗎？
I understand that you are frustrated, but you are not the victim here.
&lrm;進退兩難的局面肯定讓您煩悶不已 &lrm;但請您別太憤恨不平
That splinter cannot be
&lrm;被刺扎進指甲裡
more painful
&lrm;難道
than a sword through my chest.
&lrm;會比劍刺穿胸膛還疼嗎？
Well, then.
&lrm;那麼
We will meet again once I kill the next soul shifter.
&lrm;待我下回抓到還魂人時再見吧
Bu-yeon disappeared?
&lrm;姐姐不見了？
Look at this, my lady.
&lrm;妳看這裡
She must have climbed using this
&lrm;她貌似是踩著這個爬上去
and escaped through the window.
&lrm;從上面的窗子逃了出去
Why are these on the wall?
&lrm;這些東西為何會插在牆上？
How in the world did she do that?
&lrm;姐姐是怎麼辦到的？
I am not sure.
&lrm;我也不清楚
We must find her before Mother finds out.
&lrm;我們得在娘發現之前趕緊找到她
She has the tracking bracelet.
&lrm;她手腕上綁著追躡絲
It may take some time, but we will eventually find her.
&lrm;也許會花一些時間 &lrm;但我們一定能找到她
Last time, they caught me in four hours.
&lrm;我上回逃出來僅兩個時辰就被找到
I must meet my betrothed before then.
&lrm;我必須在那之前見到我的未婚夫
He is from the Seo family at Seoho Fortress.
&lrm;他是來自西湖城的徐家人
He will temporarily stay at Chwiseonru upon arrival.
&lrm;他抵達後會暫住取仙樓
Chwiseonru.
&lrm;取仙樓
A man from the Seo family who will come from Seoho Fortress?
&lrm;妳要找來自西湖城的徐家男人？
That is right.
&lrm;沒錯
I heard he will be staying there.
&lrm;我聽聞他將在此留宿
Yes. We do have reservations.
&lrm;是的，恰好有人預約客房
There are two of them. Which one of them are you looking for?
&lrm;不過預約人有兩位 &lrm;妳要找哪一位呢？
A man who is excellent husband material.
&lrm;他是和任何人相比 &lrm;都毫不遜色的夫婿人選
I see.
&lrm;原來如此
Then it must be Young Master Seo Yul.
&lrm;那應該是徐律少爺
Seo Yul?
&lrm;徐律？
Have you never heard of him?
&lrm;妳沒聽說過徐律嗎？
You must not be from Daeho Fortress.
&lrm;可見妳不是大湖城的人
Every woman here knows about him.
&lrm;大湖城可沒有女人不知道他
I cannot reveal a guest's information to a stranger.
&lrm;恕我不能隨意透露住客的身分
Can you tell me more in detail?
&lrm;我想再聽妳細說
Check if this is authentic or not.
&lrm;檢查一下這是否為真品
Yes, my lady.
&lrm;是
There are four men
&lrm;我們大湖城裡
at Daeho Fortress whom all the women want to marry.
&lrm;有每個女人都覬覦的四大夫婿人選
First.
&lrm;第一位
The prince who will sit on the throne one day.
&lrm;未來將登上大湖國王位的王子
Crown Prince Go Won.
&lrm;高元世子邸下
He is single, but not everyone can marry him.
&lrm;雖然他未婚，但他可不是 &lrm;人人皆能覬覦的對象
The next candidate is from the wealthiest family here.
&lrm;接下來是來自大湖城最富裕的家族
He is the new leader of Songrim, Park Dang-gu.
&lrm;松林的新任首領，朴當具
His wedding fell through at the very last minute.
&lrm;他有幾近離婚的解除婚約經歷
But that is not a big deal.
&lrm;但那點過去不算什麼
The third candidate is Seo Yul.
&lrm;還有一位就是徐律
He is from the most distinguished family and lacks nothing.
&lrm;他來自大湖國最顯赫的家族 &lrm;各方面都很優秀
But the catch is that his hometown is Seoho Fortress.
&lrm;缺點是老家在西湖城
It is too far away.
&lrm;距此十分遙遠
And lastly, there is Jang Uk.
&lrm;第四位是張煜
He is probably the strongest man in the world right now.
&lrm;他大概是目前世上最強的男人
But I do not recommend him.
&lrm;但我絕對不推薦他
Why not?
&lrm;為何？
You should never date a man with a past as painful as a stab to the heart.
&lrm;妳不能和一個懷揣著 &lrm;有如劍刺心般傷痛的男人在一起
So among those men, you are here to meet Seo Yul, right?
&lrm;所以在這幾位公子當中 &lrm;妳是來見徐律的吧？
I believe so.
&lrm;我想應該是
When is he coming?
&lrm;他何時會來？
The boat that departed from Seoho Fortress will arrive soon.
&lrm;從西湖城出發的船隻差不多要進港了
He should be here shortly.
&lrm;他應該很快就會到這
By the way, what is your relationship with him?
&lrm;不過兩位是什麼關係？
You talked about him being a husband. Are you his betrothed?
&lrm;妳方才提到他是夫婿人選 &lrm;那妳是他的未婚妻嗎？
I will only make that decision
&lrm;婚事是否談得成
after we meet and discuss the matter.
&lrm;要待我見到他 &lrm;並和他商談過後再做決定
Goodness, you are confident.
&lrm;天啊，妳真是自信十足
He is not someone you can have solely based on good looks.
&lrm;他不是妳光憑美貌就能追到手的人
Which family are you from?
&lrm;妳是哪家的小姐呢？
Madam.
&lrm;客棧主人
It is indeed authentic,
&lrm;這確實是真品
but this is the crest of Jinyowon.
&lrm;但這是辰曜院的家徽
She is offering something from Jinyowon?
&lrm;她隨隨便便就交出辰曜院的物品？
She must be a thief.
&lrm;她該不會是小偷吧？
My lady.
&lrm;小姐
What is your relationship with Jinyowon?
&lrm;妳和辰曜院有何關係？
How suspicious.
&lrm;真可疑
I must go there and check if this is really yours.
&lrm;看來我得去一趟辰曜院 &lrm;確認此物是否真屬妳所有
Get her! Get that thief!
&lrm;抓住她！抓住那個小偷！
Hello, my lord.
&lrm;首領好
-Is Yul here? -He has not arrived yet.
&lrm;-阿律到了嗎？ &lrm;-他尚未抵達
He will be arriving on a boat.
&lrm;既然他是搭船來的
Probably from over there.
&lrm;應該會在那裡下船
If he lacks nothing,
&lrm;若他各方面都很優秀
he must be handsome too.
&lrm;想必相貌也不凡
Excuse me. Are you from the Seo family?
&lrm;打擾了，請問你是徐家人嗎？
No, I am not.
&lrm;雖然我不姓徐
But I would like to know your name.
&lrm;但我想請教妳的大名
Forget it, then.
&lrm;不姓徐的話就算了
This boat will depart for Bisan-dong in the capital.
&lrm;這艘船將開往京城的飛山洞
Have you been well,
&lrm;你一切安好嗎？
Young Master Seo?
&lrm;徐律少爺
-Goodbye.
&lrm;-唉唷，辛苦你了 &lrm;-哪裡
If my betrothed accepts my mother's wishes,
&lrm;倘若要跟我成親的人想法和娘一致
I will be locked up there forever.
&lrm;我就得被關在那裡一輩子
I must speak with him before I get caught.
&lrm;我得趁被抓回去之前確認才行
What should I do?
&lrm;該怎麼辦？
Look over there.
&lrm;你看那邊
Is he not Jang Uk?
&lrm;那個人是張煜對吧？
He is Young Master Jang from the Jang family.
&lrm;他是張家的張煜少爺
Is that man over there Jang Uk?
&lrm;那個男人名叫張煜嗎？
-Yes, he is. -Yes.
&lrm;-是的
Jang Uk.
&lrm;張煜
The fourth candidate.
&lrm;第四個人選
He is probably the strongest man in the world right now.
&lrm;他大概是目前世上最強的男人
The strongest man?
&lrm;最強的人？
I heard that people avoid you.
&lrm;聽聞大家都對你避而遠之
So it is true.
&lrm;原來是事實
You must have successfully escaped.
&lrm;看來妳順利逃出來了
Right. You said it was just an outing.
&lrm;不，應該說是出門嗎？
Yes, thanks to you.
&lrm;多虧了你
I smell something delicious.
&lrm;有一股好香的味道
Can I have one of those?
&lrm;我可以來一份那個嗎？
Never mind. I have no money.
&lrm;算了，我身上也沒錢
Here is your strong liquor, my lord.
&lrm;這是你平常喝的烈酒
Excuse me.
&lrm;不好意思
I want one of those.
&lrm;給我一份那個
Yes, my lord.
&lrm;是
Thanks, Jang Uk.
&lrm;謝謝你，張煜
How do you know my name?
&lrm;妳怎麼知道我的名字？
I learned it by accident
&lrm;偶然得知的
while searching for my betrothed.
&lrm;在找尋我未婚夫的時候
Betrothed?
&lrm;未婚夫？
I will get married soon.
&lrm;我馬上就要成親了
He will move into Jinyowon.
&lrm;對方要入贅進辰曜院
Even regular priestesses' husbands move in there?
&lrm;辰曜院連一般神女 &lrm;也要招女婿入贅嗎？
Of course not.
&lrm;當然不是
Only the heir of the Jin family brings in her husband.
&lrm;只有辰曜院的繼承人需要招贅
But that is Jin Cho-yeon.
&lrm;但辰曜院的繼承人是陳超妍
She is the second daughter.
&lrm;超妍是陳家的小女兒
The future leader of Jinyowon
&lrm;未來的辰曜院院長
will be me, the eldest daughter.
&lrm;是身為長女的我
Jin Bu-yeon.
&lrm;陳復妍
What? You are who?
&lrm;什麼？妳說妳是誰？
She died ages ago.
&lrm;她早就死了
I told you already that I died a long time ago.
&lrm;我跟你說過了 &lrm;我從很久以前就已經是個死人了
I was locked up there because I should not have existed
&lrm;我本不該存活，卻還留在這世間
in the first place.
&lrm;所以才會一直被關在那裡
My mother wants my future husband to secretly move in.
&lrm;我娘想偷偷招女婿入贅
She wants me to give birth to an heir.
&lrm;要我替辰曜院傳宗接代
But if I do get married, I will be stuck in that room forever.
&lrm;倘若我真的成親 &lrm;就會永遠被困在那個房間
So you are Jin Bu-yeon.
&lrm;所以妳是陳復妍
And you want to run away and not get married?
&lrm;而妳不願成親，因此要逃跑嗎？
I cannot flee.
&lrm;我根本逃不了
So I wanted to find my betrothed and ask for his help.
&lrm;所以我原本打算去找未婚夫向他求情
But I just came up with a great idea.
&lrm;但方才我想到了一個好主意
I should find a husband who suits me instead.
&lrm;我乾脆找一個適合我的夫婿
Speaking of which,
&lrm;所以我想問你
Jang Uk.
&lrm;張煜
Will you marry me?
&lrm;你願意和我成親嗎？
What?
&lrm;什麼？
I want you to be my husband.
&lrm;我希望你當我的夫婿
There are no mages who train at Jeongjingak anymore.
&lrm;如今沒有任何術士在精進閣修煉了
There is only Uk.
&lrm;只剩下張煜一人
But he was the reason
&lrm;雖然就是因為他
why everyone left.
&lrm;大家才會離開
I left first.
&lrm;我是第一個離去的
I fled by myself
&lrm;在你和阿煜最難受的時候
when you two were struggling the most.
&lrm;只有我一個人逃也似地離開這裡
I am sorry.
&lrm;對不起
You were struggling too.
&lrm;你當時也不好受
You knew,
&lrm;阿律
did you not?
&lrm;你也早就察覺到了吧？
That she was Naksu.
&lrm;她就是落壽
Yes.
&lrm;沒錯
Uk was the first to recognize her.
&lrm;阿煜是最先看出她是落壽的人
But I was the first to meet Naksu.
&lrm;但我是最早與落壽相遇的人
We only met once, but you want me to marry you?
&lrm;妳向僅有一面之緣的男人求婚？
You must be out of your mind.
&lrm;妳一定是瘋了
-I should have never helped you escape. -I am not out of my mind.
&lrm;我鑄成大錯了 &lrm;竟然幫助被關起來的瘋子逃出來
You are strong enough to go against my mother.
&lrm;你強大到足以反抗我娘
And you have bad blood with Jinyowon.
&lrm;而且你和辰曜院關係不融洽
If we get married, she might kick me out.
&lrm;若我們成親，我說不定會被逐出家門
That is exactly what I want.
&lrm;那正是我想要的
I cannot believe I ran into the perfect potential husband.
&lrm;沒想到初次見面 &lrm;我就能遇到如此完美的夫婿人選
the craziest potential bride
&lrm;我們只不過見了一次面
when we only met once.
&lrm;我怎會遇到如此瘋狂的妻子人選？
-So you see me as a potential bride? -No.
&lrm;-你把我當妻子人選了嗎？ &lrm;-並沒有
Look me in the eye.
&lrm;你看著我
Look at me and reconsider.
&lrm;認真看著我重新考慮一次
Do you not want to wed me?
&lrm;你不想和我成親嗎？
Why?
&lrm;憑什麼？
Because…
&lrm;就憑…
my beauty is unmatched.
&lrm;我是絕世美女
You are driving me crazy.
&lrm;我要被妳搞瘋了
You cannot deny the fact
&lrm;你無法否認吧
that I turn heads wherever I go.
&lrm;我走到哪大家都盯著我看 &lrm;可謂絕代佳人
I am sure you can see for yourself.
&lrm;你有眼睛，肯定能明白
Yes, you are beautiful.
&lrm;是啊，妳是美女
I hope you find a better match with that beauty of yours.
&lrm;妳就憑藉美貌 &lrm;去尋找更完美的夫婿人選吧
Enjoy the chicken.
&lrm;妳享用完雞肉再走吧
Jang Uk.
&lrm;張煜
You.
&lrm;我說妳
Do you think I am a pushover?
&lrm;我不過稍微配合妳 &lrm;妳就認為我好欺負啊？
That is enough.
&lrm;到此為止吧
That looks good.
&lrm;看起來很美味
Enjoy your outing and go home.
&lrm;既然都出門了 &lrm;妳就吃飽玩夠再回去吧
Darn it. They will catch me soon.
&lrm;可惡，我很快就會被逮到了
There is one thing that bothers me.
&lrm;有件事讓我很在意
Seeing how they are determined to find you,
&lrm;看她們找妳找得那麼認真
you must not be just some lousy priestess.
&lrm;妳確實不是什麼小神女
Are you really Jin Bu-yeon?
&lrm;妳真的是陳復妍嗎？
Yes. I am her.
&lrm;沒錯，我就是陳復妍
She went missing ages ago.
&lrm;她很久以前就失蹤了
But they found me three years ago.
&lrm;她們三年前找到人了，就是我
They also found a fake daughter back then.
&lrm;她們三年前也曾找了一個冒牌女兒
If I were fake, why would they hide me for all those years?
&lrm;如果我是冒牌貨 &lrm;她們沒必要把我藏三年吧？
I am the real Bu-yeon.
&lrm;我是真正的陳復妍
Then again, I did hear
&lrm;也是，我聽聞陳復妍跟妳一樣
that Bu-yeon could see energy.
&lrm;能夠用肉眼看見力量
And you saw the ice stone within me.
&lrm;妳看到我體內的石頭了吧？
That is right.
&lrm;沒錯
I am the eldest daughter with the greatest divine powers.
&lrm;我是辰曜院神力最高強的長女
If my looks do not move you,
&lrm;若我的外貌不足以吸引你
consider my skills.
&lrm;那就考慮我的能力吧
You might need my help one day.
&lrm;你說不定哪天會需要我
All right.
&lrm;那好
If I ever need your help,
&lrm;以後需要妳的時候
I will find you then.
&lrm;我會去找妳
I will get married on the full moon of this month.
&lrm;這個月15日夜晚將舉行婚禮
And once I do, I will never be able to leave that room.
&lrm;我一旦成親，就無法逃離那個房間了
I need a new groom to avoid that fate.
&lrm;我若想免於那種命運 &lrm;就需要另找一位夫婿
I would like you to come and take me away.
&lrm;我希望你來帶我走
I will be waiting.
&lrm;我會等你
Please come for me.
&lrm;你務必要來
Jang Uk.
&lrm;張煜
Everyone seems to avoid you.
&lrm;我發現大家都在迴避你
Just get married while you still can.
&lrm;有女人對你有意就成親吧
I am willing to marry you.
&lrm;我願意嫁給你
Forget it.
&lrm;算了吧
There you are.
&lrm;原來妳在這裡
Let us go.
&lrm;跟我們回去吧
Have you been well, my lord?
&lrm;首領，你過得好嗎？
I am no longer the leader of Songrim.
&lrm;我已經不是首領了
Dang-gu is the leader now.
&lrm;他才是
Come on.
&lrm;唉唷
Uncle.
&lrm;叔父
I feel uneasy whenever someone calls me that.
&lrm;每當有人稱我為首領 &lrm;我內心便十分沉重
Can you take the position again
&lrm;讓我當個副首領就好
and let me just assist you?
&lrm;你可以重新回來當首領嗎？
Forget it.
&lrm;別說了
I have become so carefree.
&lrm;我現在無事一身輕
What do you do these days?
&lrm;你最近都在做什麼呢？
I farm and do housework.
&lrm;我會種種田，也會打理家務
Yul,
&lrm;阿律
I have prepared a grand feast just for you.
&lrm;我為了歡迎你 &lrm;準備了一桌豐盛的飯菜
Did you do the cooking, Uncle?
&lrm;叔父，你下廚了嗎？
He should have a taste too.
&lrm;總不能只有你一個人品嚐吧
Yul, you can look forward to it.
&lrm;阿律，你儘管拭目以待
He is right. I cannot be the only victim.
&lrm;說得沒錯，不能只有我遭殃
You should have a taste as well.
&lrm;阿律，你也應該試試看
Here comes another victim.
&lrm;又來了個一起共患難的傢伙
You are back.
&lrm;你回來啦？
Yes, I am back.
&lrm;對，我回來了
I dug out this deodeok myself, added a bit of red pepper paste,
&lrm;這是我親自挖的羊乳 &lrm;上面稍微塗點辣椒醬
and charbroiled it.
&lrm;再用炭火烤製而成
Is it not fragrant?
&lrm;味道很香吧？
This was deodeok?
&lrm;這是羊乳嗎？
I did not know.
&lrm;我都沒吃出來
Yul must have a dull palate.
&lrm;看來阿律的味覺很遲鈍
Right? Try savoring it.
&lrm;對吧？你們感受一下它的香氣
It has a strange smell.
&lrm;這香氣真稀奇
I truly appreciate your thoughtfulness.
&lrm;我很感激你的好意
But I cannot eat this anymore.
&lrm;但我再也吃不下去了
I understand.
&lrm;好吧，那個…
It may not be to your liking.
&lrm;菜色可能不太合你胃口
-Right.
&lrm;-是 &lrm;-好
Dang-gu and Uk can have the rest.
&lrm;那當具和阿煜把它吃光吧
I am delighted to see you three
&lrm;時隔許久看到你們三人相聚
sitting before me once again.
&lrm;讓我很是開心
Cheers.
&lrm;乾杯
-Eat up.
&lrm;-多吃點 &lrm;-你多吃一點
Park Dang-gu of Songrim is aware
&lrm;松林的朴當具
that we are preparing for a wedding?
&lrm;知道婚禮用品送到我們家一事？
Yes, my lady.
&lrm;是的
I heard that he kept asking who the bride was.
&lrm;據說他窮追不捨地問是誰要成親
Since he does not know about Bu-yeon,
&lrm;他不曉得姐姐的事
we should tell him it is me.
&lrm;八成是誤以為我要成親了
I loved you, Jin Cho-yeon.
&lrm;我愛過妳，陳超妍
I hope you will be happy!
&lrm;祝妳幸福
I miss you so much…
&lrm;就算沒有我也要過得幸福
I will tuck him in.
&lrm;我送他回房間休息
-Sure. -Jin Cho-yeon…
&lrm;-好 &lrm;-陳超妍…
-I loved you, Jin Cho-yeon. -Bye.
&lrm;-陳超妍，我愛過妳 &lrm;-我走了
I loved you so much…
&lrm;我愛過妳
That poor kid.
&lrm;當具那小子
Seeing how drunk he is,
&lrm;看他醉成那樣
Sang-ho must have been right about a wedding happening in Jinyowon.
&lrm;難道相豪說辰曜院 &lrm;要舉行婚禮一事為真嗎？
There really is a wedding taking place in Jinyowon?
&lrm;辰曜院當真要舉行婚禮嗎？
I heard they brought in wedding supplies.
&lrm;聽說婚禮要用的物品被送了過去
They locked their gate and lay low for the past three years.
&lrm;他們三年來大門緊閉 &lrm;過著低調的生活
I guess the wedding will be held in secret as well.
&lrm;看來連婚禮也打算悄然無聲地舉行
Do you know who the bride is?
&lrm;你知道是誰要成親嗎？
Jin Cho-yeon, probably.
&lrm;應該是陳超妍吧
She is the only daughter of the family.
&lrm;陳家只有她一個女兒
There is also the eldest daughter.
&lrm;還有長女陳復妍啊
But she is dead.
&lrm;那孩子已經死了
She was trying to retrieve the ice stone that was sealed in the lake
&lrm;她找出被封印在敬天大湖的冰石之際
when the waters swept her away.
&lrm;遭湖水捲走而喪命
Her father came clean
&lrm;那孩子的父親
about everything before he died.
&lrm;在死前道出了實情
Her death was such a waste.
&lrm;真是可惜了那個孩子
With the divine powers she had at such a young age,
&lrm;她小小年紀就有那般神力的話
she would have grown to be as powerful as Jin Seol-ran,
&lrm;應該會成為僅次於 &lrm;辰曜院首任院長陳雪蘭的
the first leader of Jinyowon.
&lrm;神女
If a priestess
&lrm;假如
as powerful as Jin Seol-ran exists,
&lrm;有個媲美陳雪蘭的神女
will she be able to extract the ice stone within me?
&lrm;她能將我體內的冰石之力取出嗎？
If she can,
&lrm;若能那麼做
would you extract it?
&lrm;你想將它取出來嗎？
You are only alive thanks to that stone.
&lrm;你是因為擁有那股力量才得以活著
You said the ice stone
&lrm;你說過冰石之力
should be destroyed since no human can control its power.
&lrm;人類無法承受，因此必須銷毀
Yes.
&lrm;是的
You are right.
&lrm;你說得沒錯
It is too much for me…
&lrm;它令我…
to handle.
&lrm;難以承受
Maidservant Kim told me
&lrm;金道主說
that it was too painful to watch you live
&lrm;你心中彷彿一直插著一把劍
with a wounded heart.
&lrm;光看著你就感到心酸
Is it still very painful?
&lrm;你依然感到很疼痛嗎？
I should have died then.
&lrm;我當時應該死的
As a human,
&lrm;當場死亡
I should have died then and there.
&lrm;是我身為人所能承受的極限
Do you think removing the ice stone
&lrm;你覺得取出你體內的冰石
would heal your wounded heart?
&lrm;刺在心上的那把劍 &lrm;也會被隨之拔除嗎？
But if you do that,
&lrm;但要是你那麼做
you will die.
&lrm;你必死無疑
At least…
&lrm;最起碼
I will lift the weight off my shoulders and finally be at peace.
&lrm;我可以卸下重擔並得到安寧
Uncle Yun-o,
&lrm;潤娛叔父
you are getting married?
&lrm;你要成親？
You never told me.
&lrm;你沒有跟我提過啊
It was meant to be a secret, so I could not tell you.
&lrm;這是一樁祕密促成的婚事 &lrm;我也沒辦法告訴你
I will be wedding the eldest daughter of Jinyowon, Jin Bu-yeon.
&lrm;我今晚要和辰曜院的長女陳復妍成親
It is our tradition to have the wedding at the groom's place
&lrm;按照辰曜院的傳統，新娘在婚禮過後
and then return to Jinyowon with him.
&lrm;要帶著新郎進辰曜院
What is that?
&lrm;那是什麼？
A petal?
&lrm;是花瓣呢
It came to me when I was at my most desperate.
&lrm;它在我最絕望的時刻來找我
I hope it will return.
&lrm;我希望它會回來
I know you hate it, but you should not run away again.
&lrm;妳再怎麼不願意 &lrm;也不能再有逃跑的念頭
I know.
&lrm;我知道
I am waiting.
&lrm;我只是在等待
Waiting? For whom?
&lrm;等待？妳在等誰？
My groom.
&lrm;我的夫婿
Please come and take me away.
&lrm;拜託來帶我走
The bride has left Jinyowon
&lrm;新娘從辰曜院出發了
and will be here soon.
&lrm;應該很快就會抵達
Is he the one Bu-yeon will wed tonight?
&lrm;那位是今日要與姐姐成親的人嗎？
Yes.
&lrm;沒錯
He is the cousin of General Seo of Seoho Fortress
&lrm;他是西湖城徐日將軍與王妃娘娘的
and the Queen.
&lrm;堂弟
He lost his parents early
&lrm;他父母早逝
and has no one to rely on.
&lrm;背後沒有支持他的勢力
He needs our help,
&lrm;他需要辰曜院的力量
so I can be assured that he will do well.
&lrm;進來後會有一番表現的
He will not be able
&lrm;那個人
to free my sister.
&lrm;無法救出被困住的姐姐
I guess he will not come.
&lrm;他可能不會來了吧
I knew it.
&lrm;我就知道
I knew you would come.
&lrm;你會來接我
You might be of some use.
&lrm;我可能會需要妳
I told you I would be useful.
&lrm;我說過我會有用處的
Let us go.
&lrm;我們走吧
Sure.
&lrm;好
Let us go, my dear husband.
&lrm;走吧，我的夫婿
ALCHEMY OF SOULS PART 2
&lrm;還魂 &lrm;第二部
You see, I remember nothing before Jinyowon.
&lrm;其實我沒有進入辰曜院前的記憶
Search all of Songrim and find Park Dang-gu.
&lrm;仔細搜查松林，找出朴當具
I thought the wedding ceremony was for Young Lady Jin.
&lrm;我以為那是超妍小姐的婚禮
Although I wanted to ruin the ceremony, I did not.
&lrm;雖然我想立刻去毀了那場婚禮 &lrm;但我並沒有那麼做
WHOEVER FINDS THIS LADY WILL BE REWARDED GENEROUSLY
&lrm;（找到此人並提供消息者 &lrm;必將重金答謝，松林）
The entire world ended up finding out about Bu-yeon.
&lrm;復妍的存在終究被公諸於世了
Were you going to ask her to take out the ice stone for you?
&lrm;你認為她能幫你取出冰石嗎？
Have we ever met before?
&lrm;我總覺得我們似乎在哪見過
What is it that you need me for?
&lrm;我對你來說有什麼用處？
I just need your great divine powers. That is why I need you.
&lrm;只要妳擁有那股強大的神力 &lrm;對我來說就有用處
Subtitle translation by: Soo-ji Kim
&lrm;字幕翻譯：吳盈臻